{"data":[{"question":"There are only five minutes ___,","a":"to leave","b":"to be left","c":"left","d":"leaving","answer":"3","explain":"\n- Structure: there's sth\/nothing left","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"73","subcategorylv2":"14","type":"1"},{"question":"Mainland China is a ___ country, while U.S.A. is a ___ country.","a":"developed, developed","b":"developing, developing","c":"developed, developing","d":"developing, developed","answer":"4","explain":"\n- Participle can be used as an adjective to describe a noun: \n+ Ing - form: describe something in progress \n+ Ed- form:describe completed thing","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"73","subcategorylv2":"14","type":"1"},{"question":"The legislator returned to his office, ___ by two secretaries.","a":"followed","b":"following","c":"by following","d":"follow","answer":"1","explain":"\n- A participle is a verb form which can be used as an adjective to describe a noun \n+When the present participle (-ing from) is used, the noun it describes is (or was) the performer of the activity named by the participle \n+ When the past participle (-ed, -en form) is used, the noun it describes is (or was) acted upon \n- When a participle phrase introduces a main clause, separate the two sentence components with a comma ","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"73","subcategorylv2":"14","type":"1"},{"question":"The veteran's body was covered with a national flag, ___.","a":"to have his face exposing","b":"left his face exposed","c":"leaving his face exposed","d":"leaving has face exposing","answer":"3","explain":"\n- A participle is a verb form which can be used as an adjective to describe a noun \n+When the present participle (-ing from) is used, the noun it describes is (or was) the performer of the activity named by the participle \n+ When the past participle (-ed, -en form) is used, the noun it describes is (or was) acted upon \n- When a participle phrase introduces a main clause, separate the two sentence components with a comma","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"73","subcategorylv2":"14","type":"1"},{"question":"The examinees are busy ___ for the examination.","a":"preparing","b":"prepare","c":"to be prepared","d":"to prepare","answer":"1","explain":"\n- Present continuous tense: to be + Verb_ing","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"73","subcategorylv2":"14","type":"1"},{"question":"___ here in time, Alice came ___ all the way.","a":"To get, running","b":"Getting, running","c":"To get, to run","d":"To be getting, to run","answer":"1","explain":"\n- Clause started with \"to + Verb\" implies the purpose of action \n- Come running\/flying\/speeding etc: Continue doing something","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"73","subcategorylv2":"14","type":"1"},{"question":"The naughty boy stood beside his mother, ___ a face at her.","a":"made","b":"to make","c":"make","d":"making","answer":"4","explain":"\n- A participle is a verb form which can be used as an adjective to describe a noun \n+When the present participle (-ing from) is used, the noun it describes is (or was) the performer of the activity named by the participle \n+ When the past participle (-ed, -en form) is used, the noun it describes is (or was) acted upon \n- When a participle phrase introduces a main clause, separate the two sentence components with a comma","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"73","subcategorylv2":"14","type":"1"},{"question":"It is no use _________ over spilt milk.","a":"to cry","b":"cry","c":"be crying","d":"crying","answer":"4","explain":"\n- Structure: It's no use doing sth","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"73","subcategorylv2":"14","type":"1"},{"question":"There is ___ how the climate may change.","a":"no knowing","b":"not knowing","c":"no known","d":"not know","answer":"1","explain":"\n- There's no knowing: it is impossible to know","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"73","subcategorylv2":"14","type":"1"},{"question":"___ made us much disappointed.","a":"Not Frank coming back","b":"Frank not coming back","c":"Not Frank come back","d":"Frank not to come back","answer":"2","explain":"\n- A participle is a verb form which can be used as an adjective to describe a noun \n+When the present participle (-ing from) is used, the noun it describes is (or was) the performer of the activity named by the participle \n+ When the past participle (-ed, -en form) is used, the noun it describes is (or was) acted upon \n- When a participle phrase concludes a main clause and is describing the word right in front of it, you need no punctuation to connect the two sentence parts","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"73","subcategorylv2":"14","type":"1"}]}